Before we switch to the code example,
コードの例に切り替える前に、
you defines the posterior in this way.
ここで事後確率を定義します
You already learned that the tiny details that over
あなたは観測ベクターが多くのデータにもなりうることを
here are observation vector could be a lot of data,
既に学習しました
and we do not want to carry the whole observation history to estimate the state beliefs.
また 状態信念を推定するために観測履歴全体を実行したくはありません
The idea is now,
アイデアは次のようになります
that we manipulate the posterior over here,
再帰的な状態推定器が得られるように
such in a way that you get a recursive state estimator.
ここで事後確率を操作するという考え方です
We have to show that the current belief over here,
ここの現在の信念が
can be expressed by a belief one step earlier and
1 つ前のステップの信念で表現できることを実証し
then update the current belief only with new observation information.
新しい観測情報で現在の信念を更新します
We call this estimator the Bayes Localization Filter or Markov Localization.
この推定するものをベイズローカライゼーションフィルターまたは Markov Localization と呼びます
This will allow us to avoid having to carry
これで 過去の観測値とモーションデータを
around all historical observation and motion data.
すべて持ち歩かなくて済みます
To achieve this recursive structure,
この再帰的構造を達成するには
you have to apply probabilistic rules and laws like the Bayes Rule,
ベイズルールや全確率の公式などの
or The Law of Total Probability.
確率の規則や公式を適用する必要があります
You already heard about this in Sebastian's Lessons.
既にセバスチャンのレッスンでこれについて聞かれたことでしょう
So, this should not be something new for you.
だから 初めて耳にすることではないと思います
I will also teach about The Markov Assumption.
マルコフの仮定についても説明します
This involves, making meaningful assumptions
これには ある値間での依存について
about the dependencies between on certain values.
マーケティングで意味のある仮定がかかわってきます
So our goal on the next steps is to define the posterior in a recursive way.
そこで 次のステップでの目標は 再帰的な方法で事後確率を定義することです
This means, we want to fill out this box here on the right side.
これは ここの右側のこのボックスをうめたいということです
The first thing what I'm doing is,
最初に行うことは
I split a whole observation vector into
観測値ベクトル全体を
the current observations and our previous informations.
現在の観測と前の情報に分けることです
This is important to achieve the recursive structure,
これは 再帰的な構造を実現するために重要です
as a reminder you see again the definition of observations on the right side.
右側の観測の定義をもう一度見てください
Now, we apply Bayse rule.
ここでベイズルールを適用します
You already learned about Bayse rule and the previous lessons.
既に前のレッスンでベイズルールを学習したと思います
And Sebastian already told you,
確率推論において一番基礎になる考え方ですが
Bayse rule is the most fundamental consideration in probabilistic inference.
基本となる法則は非常にシンプルです
The tricky part is here,
ひっかけ部分はここで
that you have more than one variables on the right side.
右側に 1 つ以上の変数があります
Which means you have to apply Bayse rule with multiple conditions.
複数の条件でベイズルールを適用しなければならないということです
Now my question is for you.
そこで質問です
Could you apply Bayse rule for the localization posterior?
ローカライズされた事後確率にベイズルールを適用できますか?
As a hint to assume the state xt is A.
状態 xt が Aであると仮定するというのがヒントです
And the observation vectors that T is B,
また 観測ベクトル T が B です
and please do not forget the other conditions.
他の条件も忘れないでください